Eric Christine

Boulder, Colorado 80302 | 513-658-6378 | ericjchristine@gmail.com

Github | LinkedIn | Website

Full Stack Web Developer

Curious, collaborative, and coachable individual with a B.S. in Sustainability from The Ohio State University. 2021 bootcamp graduate from Flatiron School, specialized in full-stack software engineering. A strong background in business and sustainability brings transferable problem-solving and systems-thinking skills to any team or project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, React Native, WordPress, Wix

Backend: Ruby On Rails, Firebase

Additional: Git, XCode, Swift, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe Photoshop, Elementor, SEO, Google Analytics, HostGator,

Stripe, CPanel, Weebly eCommerce, WP Contact Form 7, Ninja Forms, Wix CRM, Email Campaigns

EXPERIENCE

Schwing Marketing Services

Web Developer

Denver, CO / Remote

03/2021 - Present

- Develop and optimize new and existing WordPress and Wix sites for their businesses, engage directly with clients
- Prioritize updates, decide which technologies work best for clients' needs in a remote-first environment.

Cycle Technology_

Miami, FL / Remote

Software Engineer Intern

01/2021 - Present

- Refreshed multiple pages on core website using new Wordpress plugins to replicate an Adobe XD design.
- Manage Google SEO, Wordpress Plugins, HTML iframes, and Content for a site that reaches 1900+ visits / month.

Tech Elevator

Business Development Intern

Columbus, OH 05/2019 - 08/2019

- Communicated closely with the Talent Acquisition Manager to find specific, top-talent for a rapidly growing company
- Enlisted over 30 new hiring partners to develop career opportunities for graduating Java & .NET development students.

Ohio State Student Life

Columbus, OH

Sustainability Student Lead

08/2018 - 05/2020

- Responsible for communicating with students through peer-to-peer tabling discussions, mentorship groups, and presentations.
- Consistently built Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram accounts to achieve the greatest reach and impact.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Siam Orchid Thai Restaurant - Github | Live Site

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Website refresh for a small business

- Created a responsive restaurant website for a small restaurant business.
- Designed QR-Code, mobile-first menus with animations and simple navigation. Sees 80+ user visits / day.

Buckeye Recycle - Github | Demo

React Native, Ruby on Rails

Recycling mobile app that aims to gamify recycling and reduce waste on university campuses.

- Developed skills in React Native in 2 weeks to build full stack app from scratch
- Customized search bar to pull results across several parameters

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Immersive Full Stack Web Software Engineering Program

Denver, CO Graduated 01/2021

The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH Graduated 05/2020

Bachelor's of Science in Environment, Economy, Development, & Sustainability (EEDS)